Finding Aid for Institute for Social Research (University of Michigan) publications, 1946-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Publications
  - Sub-Unit Publications
    - Survey Research Center (SRC)
      - Reports
        - Public Thinking Regarding Atomic Energy, no. 53, 1950 (Box 6)
        - Public Thinking About Atomic Warfare and Civil Defense: Five Americans State Their Conceptions of Atomic Warfare and the Problem of Civil Defense, 1950 (Box 6)
        - Public Thinking About Atomic Warfare and Civil Defense: A Study Based Upon an Intensive Interview Sample Survey of People in Eleven Major Cities, September-October 1950, 1951 (Box 6)
        - The Public's Viewpoint on Peaceful Uses for Nuclear Energy, 1955 (Box 6)
        - Rental Housing in Ann Arbor: Summary of Preliminary Findings Prepared for the Department of Housing and Urban Development Under Contract With the City of Ann Arbor, 1976 (Box 6)
        - Rental Housing in Ann Arbor: Variable Documentation, vol. 1-3, 1976; 3 folders (Box 6)
        - Study of Higher Education in Michigan, 1959 (Box 6)
        - TR (Technical Reports), 1966-1967 (Box 6)
        - Youth in Transition, 1967 (Box 6)
      - Annual Summer Institute
        - List of Foreign Visitors pre-1955-1960, 1961 (Box 7)
        - Survey Research Techniques
          - Bulletins, 1948-2001; 7 folders (Box 7)
          - Posters, 1986-2000 (Box 7)
      - Economic Behavior Program
        - Brochures, undated (Box 7)
      - Organizational Behavior and Change Program
        - Bibliographies
          - Bibliography, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Topical Publications
    The Topical Publications subseries includes brochures and flyers from events sponsored by the Institute for Social Research. The events include a symposium honoring their founder (1981), Martin Luther King Day (1989-1990) and the 50th Anniversary of ISR (1997-1998).
    - ISR 50th Anniversary, 1997-1998 (Box 7)
    - Martin Luther King Day, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
    - Third Annual Founders Symposium Honoring Dorwin P. Cartwright, 1981 (Box 7)
In addition to the collection described above, the Bentley Historical Library holds a set of 327 bound volumes of the "Publications of the Institute for Social Research." These volumes contain the collected scholarly output from surveys and studies conducted by ISR, including reports, monographs, reprints, and offprints. The publications were collected and bound by the ISR Library and each study has an ISR index number. This library was transferred to the Bentley Historical Library upon the closing of the ISR Library due to cost considerations in June 1998.
There are 327 numbered volumes and additional bound monographs in the library, ca. 1950-1995. The materials are arranged by ISR number, which is roughly chronological. The items in the library are described in the bibliographies located in Box 1 of the ISR Publications collection. The range of the collection is covered by five bibliographies: List of Publications 1946-60, 1961-1965 and 1966-1970, ISR Bibliography 1970-1990 and ISR Bibliography Author Index 1970-1994. For publications prior to 1965, the only access to the materials is by author. Beginning in 1965, the bibliographies also include a keyword index. The bibliographies include the ISR number as part of the citation for most studies.
The ISR Library Collection is shelved separately. Requests for publications should include the ISR number.